Guide to the Stillman King Wightman papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Stillman King Wightman papers
1817-1837
MS 1079
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(1 box)
The papers consist of correspondence, lecture notes, financial papers, and writings relating to Wightman's student years at Yale University and his early legal practice. Correspondents include his parents, his Yale classmates, his brother-in-law, and various young men and women (mainly from Middletown, Connecticut) who were his friends. The notes are from lectures and other activities in Yale College. The financial papers are for his college expenses.
Wightman, Stillman King, 1803-1899
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Henry H. Wightman, 1959.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Stillman King Wightman, a lawyer, was born in Scituate, Rhode Island, on January 8, 1803. He graduated from Yale in 1825 and studied at the Yale Law School. Wightman opened a practice in Middletown, Connecticut, and, from 1835-1842, held a number of state offices. In 1842 he moved to New York City where he continued an active legal practice for fifty years. Wightman died on May 27, 1899.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, lecture notes, financial papers, and writings relating to Wightman's student years at Yale University and his early legal practice. Correspondents include his parents, his Yale classmates, his brother-in-law, and various young men and women (mainly from Middletown, Connecticut) who were his friends. The notes are from lectures and other activities in Yale College. The financial papers are for his college expenses.
Law; Connecticut; Lecture notes; Lawyers; Belden, Joshua, 1766-1849; Cathin, Abijah; Dutton, Matthew Rice, 1783-1825; Ely, Selden; Goodrich, Chauncey A. (Chauncey Allen), 1790-1860; Hayes, W. R. (William R.); Kingsley, James Luce, 1778-1852; Mather, Thomas; Savage, Thomas Staughton; Silliman, Benjamin, 1816-1885; Smith, Richard, 1802-1878; Wightman, Frederick; Wightman, Mary; Wightman, Stillman King, 1803-1899; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students
- Original accession
  - Incoming letters
    - Bartlett, Jason R., 1827 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Belden, Joshua, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Butler, James (brother-in-law), 1822-1830 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Catlin, Abijah (1805-1891), 1826 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chamberlain, Elijah, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Cooke, R., 1822 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ely, Selden (Y. 1825), 1822-1824 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ford, Seabury (Y. 1825), 1827 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Gear, Hiram, 1826-1829 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hayes, William R., 1826-29 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hill, Benjamin W., 1825 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Knowlton, Miner, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Mather, Thomas, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Miner, Samuel, 1822 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Paddock, Jonathan Robert, 1825-1826 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Savage, Thomas Staughton (1804-1880; Y. 1825), 1823-1827 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - Smith, Richard (1802-78; Y. 1825), 1825-1830 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Streetor, Mary, 1823-1824 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Tarbox, Hannah, 1823 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Topliff, Stephen, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Treat, Lorenzo, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wightman, Frederick and Mary (Polley), 1822-1834 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - Wilcox, Asa F., 1822-1829 (Box 1, Folder 12-15)
    - Williams, Stephen Clay (1804-87), 1829 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Copy of letter to William Hodges of Duplin County, North Carolina, re a receipt given to Samuel Crowell, Jr., by Selden Tryon, 1837 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Notes on lectures, [1821-1825]
    - Matthew Rice Dutton on natural philosophy (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Chauncey Allen Goodrich on rhetoric and oratory (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - James Luce Kingsley on languages and chronology (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Benjamin Silliman on chemistry (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified, on mathematics and an unidentified classical text (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Compositions, notes for debates, and other student writings, [1821-1857] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bond and bills for college expenses, 1821-1825 (Box 1, Folder 20)